Eric (Binqian) Zeng

40 Memorial Hwy. Apt. 05R, New Rochelle, NY, 10801

□ +1 929-208-7103 • ☑ bz866@nyu.edu; ericzengsearch@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/bingian-zeng-257903126/ • https://github.com/bz866

Introduction

One-year working experience as a Data Scientist; Master's level education background in Machine Learning and Financial Mathematics. Python & C/C++ programmer. Skilled in quantitative/machine learning modeling. Familiar with database, big data analysis, and cloud computing. Experienced in collaborating with the trading desk and the research team. Seeking full-time opportunities in the cross of technology and finance.

Work Experience

Swiss Reinsurance Company Ltd. (Swiss Re)

Armonk, NY

Jan 2019–Present

- Analytics Specialist/Data Scientist
- * Wildfire Risk Prediction in North America
- Estimated wildfire risk in North America using meteorological and geographical data; Large fire prediction performs at precision(37%) and recall(81%) (Python, Generalized Linear Model)
- * Catastrophe Loss Impact Estimation using Machine Learning Models
 - Estimated the loss of catastrophes(wild fire, flood, etc.) using satellite images, coverage policies, and geographic data from various resources; Narrowed down the percentage error within 10% (Zonal Statistic, Random Forest Regression, CNN, Python, ArcGIS)
- * Insurance Policies Dataset Management & Cluster Configuration
 - Be the first one who aggregated metadata description for an internal big dataset(billions of records); ETL for data mining(SQL); Backtested hypothesis and correlation(SparkML); Clustering(SparkML); Configured the cloud computing clusters(Linux)
- * Home Renters Insurance Go-to-market Analysis
 - Identified home rental insurance market opportunities in New York State using self-designed opportunity scoring metrics(Significance Test, Linear Regression); Visualized in an interactive dashboard (Python, JavaScript)

King Street Capital Management, L.P.

New York, NY

Jul 2018-Dec 2018

Data Science Intern (full-time)

- * Companies KPI Forecasting Model
 - Forecasted KPIs of companies using an ensemble model; All base and top learners are SVMs with different constraints
 - Handled collinearity in meta-features by matrix factorization; Reduced overfitting by ridge regularization and noise injection; Direction prediction performs at accuracy 86% (SQL, Python, Scikit-learn, Stacked Ensemble Model)
- * Analyzing Alpha in Corporate Filings
 - Categorized companies with high and low information ratio based on corporate fillings using Tf-Idf, RNN and attention mechanism
 - Generated sentence representation with word-embedding and textual changes over time; Achieved accuracy 82% with index as benchmark

Crypto Investments

New York, NY

Sep 2017-Dec 2017

- Machine Learning Engineer Intern
- * Event-Driven Forecasting Model for Price of Cryptocurrencies
 - Web-scrapped cryptocurrencies news and trade data by API; Data management for scrapped data(Python, MongoDB)
 - News sentiment analysis by Word2Vec; Event embedding by Open IE; Captured effects of different time spans by CNN

Technical Skills & Certificates

- Programming & Scripting Language: Python, Java, C/C++, Scala, R, Matlab
- Toolkits, Softwares & Operating Systems: SQL, Spark, Hadoop, AWS, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, NLTK, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Github, Linux/Unix

Education

New York University, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

New York, NY

Mathematics in Finance; part-time graduate program on-going

Jan 2019 – Present

Courseworks: Derivative Securities, Operating System(C/C++), Risk and Portfolio Management with Econometrics, Financial Modeling, Algorithmic Trading & Quantitative Strategies

New York University, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

New York, NY

M.S Data Science; GPA: 3.3/4.0;

Sep 2016 – May 2018

Courseworks: Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing(Kyunghyun Cho), Deep Learning(Yann LeCun), Statistical and Mathematical Methods, Big Data(Hadoop MapReduce, Spark), Data Science in Quantitative Finance, Advance Python Programming

Sun Yat-sen University, School of Engineering

Guangzhou, China Sep 2012 – Jun 2016

B.E Engineering Mechanics (Fluid Dynamics Focus); GPA: 3.7/4.0; Honor: Annual scholarship (three years) Courseworks: Numerical Methods, Finite element analysis, Ordinary Differential Equations, Fluid Dynamics

Portfolio

Operating System Components

- \sim **Keywords:** C/C++, Operating System, Object-oriented Programming
- Linker; Process Scheduler(discrete event simulation model); Virtual Memory Management Unit; I/O Scheduler

Text Summarization Neural Network for News

- Keywords: Python, Pytorch, Bidirectional-LSTM, Attention Mechanism, Pointer Network, Semantic Relevance
- A hybrid of extractive and abstractive approaches text summarization model trained on CNN/Daily Mail news
- Bi-LSTM encoder with attention mechanism; Pointer Network improves the accuracy of words generation and the ability of handling out-of-vocabulary words; Semantic relevance encouraged loss function

Commodity Trading Position Forecasting Model

- Keywords: Python, Alpha Strategy, Matrix Factorization & Decomposition, Regularization, Linear Regression
- Created a regression model that forecasts the optimal trading positions for oil, sugar, copper, gold, and natural gas futures